in today's lesson we'll be having a look
在今天的课程中，我们将会看到
at a path effect in inkscape that allows
在Inkscape中的路径效果允许
you to draw in mirror mode it works by
您可以在镜像模式下绘制它的工作方式
creating a copy of what you've created
创建已创建内容的副本
and mirroring it on an opposing axis
并将其镜像到相反的轴上
what's more any edits that you make to
此外，您对以下内容进行的任何编辑
the original copy will also be applied
还将应用原始副本
to the mirrored copy let's have a
对于镜像副本，让我们有一个
[Music]
[音乐]
look so getting us started here at
听着，让我们在这里开始吧
inkscape the first thing I'm going to do
Inkscape我要做的第一件事
is demonstrate how this feature works
是演示该功能如何工作
and then I will give you a working
然后我会给你一份工作
example of when this sort of feature
这类功能的示例
would be useful so to start us out here
会很有用，所以让我们从这里开始
let's create a circle I'm going to grab
让我们创建一个我要抓住的圆圈
the circles and ellipses tool and I'm
圆圈和椭圆工具，我是
click and drag so we get a nice round
点击并拖动，这样我们就可以打一轮好球了
do is I'm going to use the mirror
我要做的是用镜子
symmetry path effect to create a
对称路径效果以创建
mirrored copy of this object and
此对象的镜像副本和
whatever I do to this object will also
无论我对此对象做什么，也会
happen to the mirrored object let me
发生在镜面上的物体让我
show you what I mean with the circle
告诉你我说的圆圈是什么意思
select path
选择路径
effects and from the path effects menu
效果和从路径效果菜单
plus icon down here in the bottom right
右下角的加号图标
corner I'm going to click on that to add
角，我要点击它来添加
a new path effect and the path effect
一种新的路径效应和路径效应
I'm looking for is called mirror
我要找的是一面镜子
search bar here m i r r begin typing it
这里的搜索栏m i r r开始输入
and there it is right there mirror
它就在那里，就是镜子
cloned copy over of it over here on the
它的克隆复制件在这里
right hand side now if you want to edit
如果要编辑，请立即在右侧进行编辑
this object just grab your edit paths by
这个对象只是通过以下方式获取编辑路径
nodes tool and you should notice Let Me
Nodes工具，您应该注意到，让我
zoom in on on this you should notice
放大这个，你应该会注意到
this blue line going between the two
这条介于两者之间的蓝线
objects now if I take this node in the
对象，如果将此节点放在
center and move this over like this you
居中，像这样把这个移到另一边
can see that I'm moving the object the
可以看到我正在移动物体
Clones copy away from the original one
克隆从原始拷贝中复制
and these nodes down here I can use
下面这些节点我可以使用
these nodes to rotate the Clones copy
这些节点用于旋转克隆拷贝
like that if need be the bottom one
如果需要的话，就像是最底层的那个
rotates it that way and the top one will
以这样的方式旋转，上面的那个将
rotate it this way like that okay so the
像这样旋转，好的，这样
way this works is anything I do to this
我对这件事所做的任何事情都是可行的
object will also happen to this object
对象也将发生在此对象上
so if I select this object and then make
因此，如果我选择此对象，然后使
this green both objects will become
这两个物体都会变成绿色
green if I take this node right here and
绿色，如果我把这个节点放在这里
bring in the width like that as you can
尽可能地把宽度弄成这样
see the width of the other object
查看另一个对象的宽度
changes as well like that and now we are
也发生了这样的变化，现在我们
drawing in mirror symmetry so once I'm
画出镜面对称性，所以一旦我
finished using this effect and I want to
已使用完此效果，我想
finalize this I can go to path object to
完成此操作后，我可以转到路径对象
path and if I grab my nodes tool I
路径，如果我抓住我的节点工具
already have it selected you can see
已经选择了它，您可以看到
these are now two individual paths these
这些现在是两条单独的路径
are no longer linked as mirrored copies
不再作为镜像拷贝链接
these were just individual paths that
这些只是单独的路径，
were created from a mirrored copy and
是从镜像副本创建的，
that's prettyy much the basics of how
这很好地说明了如何
the mirror symmetry path effect works in
镜像对称路径效果在
inkscape so let's have a look at a
Inkscape，让我们来看看
working example of when something like
以下内容的工作示例：
this would be useful the example I'm
这会对我的例子很有用
going to use here is creating an emoji
这里要使用的是创建一个表情符号
smiley face so let me grab my circles
笑脸，所以让我抓住我的圆圈
and ellipses tool I'm going to click and
和省略号工具，我要点击和
drag on the canvas like that I'm going
像这样拖着画布，我要走了
to hold control and I want to make my
掌握控制权，我想让我的
smiley face yellow I'm going to grab the
黄色笑脸我要去拿
selection tool I'm going to duplicate
我要复制的选择工具
this circle by pressing control D I'll
按下CONTROL D这个圆圈，我会
make this copy white and then I'll hold
把这份复印件印成白色，然后我会拿着
contr control and shift and I'll scale
控制和换档，我会调整的
this down like that this circle right
这个像那个，这个圆圈就对了
here is actually going to represent a
这里实际上将表示一个
smile the bottom half of the circle
对着圆圈的下半部分微笑
anyway it's going to be the smiling uh
不管怎么说，那就是微笑吧
face of the uh Emoji here and so in
嗯，表情符号的脸在这里，等等
order to turn this into a smiley I need
为了把它变成我需要的笑脸
to cut off this bottom part right here
把下面的这部分剪掉
I'm going to use the rectangle tool to
我将使用矩形工具来
do that I'm going to click and drag to
这样做，我将单击并拖动到
create a rectangle going over that
在上面创建一个矩形
bottom half like that I'm going to
像这样的下半身，我要
change this to a different color cuz I'd
把这个换成不同的颜色因为我会
like to be able to see this rectangle
希望能看到这个长方形
I'll make this red and I will bring down
我会把它染成红色，我会把它拿下来
the opacity of this as well I'll just
这也是不透明的，我只想
make this something like 50 just so I
把这个弄成50美元左右，这样我就能
can see through it there and if you
在那里可以看穿它，如果你
notice the intersecting area between the
注意两个区域之间的交叉区域
circle and the red rectangle is going to
圆圈和红色矩形将显示为
represent the smiley face so I'm going
代表笑脸，所以我要去
to grab the selection tool hold shift
要抓取选择工具，请按住Shift键
click on the circle so we have both the
点击圆圈，这样我们就可以同时拥有
rectangle and the circle selected and go
矩形和选定的圆，然后继续
to path and select intersection and
设置路径并选择交点和
there is the smile part of the Emoji now
表情符号现在有了微笑的部分
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
我要做的是我要
create a single eye up here and then I'm
在上面画一只眼睛，然后我就
going to use the mirror symmetry path
将使用镜像对称路径
effect to create the other eye for the
创建另一只眼睛
other side so that I can adjust the two
另一边，这样我就可以调整这两个
eyes together at the same time so let me
眼睛同时在一起，所以让我
grab the uh circles and ellipses tool
抓起呃圆圈和椭圆形工具
click and drag to create a circle hold
单击并拖动以创建圆形保持
control like that let me make this white
像这样的控制让我把它变成白色
let me bring the opacity of this back up
让我把这件事的不透明带回来
to
至
100% grab the selection tool now for
100%立即抓取选择工具
what I want to do the way I want to edit
我想要做的事情我想要编辑的方式
this I want to convert this circle into
这个我想把这个圆圈变成
a path so let me go to path and choose
一条小路，所以让我去小路上选择
object to path and that's now a path
对象到路径，这现在是一个路径
with nodes on it rather than a circle
上面有节点，而不是圆圈
object so let me right click this and go
对象，所以让我右键单击它，然后继续
to duplicate I'll make this one black
为了复制，我会把这个改成黑色
I'm going to hold control and shift like
我要保持控制并像这样换挡
that scale that down and maybe even move
缩小规模，甚至可能搬家
that down a little bit like that so what
像这样往下一点，那又怎么样？
I'm going to do is I want to group these
我要做的是我想把这些分组
two objects together the White and the
两个物体在一起，白色和
black circle and I want to group them
黑圈和我想把他们分组
together as a single unit so that I can
作为一个整体，这样我就可以
mirror both objects at the same time so
同时镜像两个对象，以便
I'm going to hold shift and click on the
我要按住Shift键并单击
circle with them both selected go to
将这两个选项都选中的圆圈转到
object group and now I'm going to mirror
对象组，现在我要镜像
the grouped object so I'm going to click
分组的对象，所以我要单击
the plus icon down here again our path
下面的加号图标再次显示了我们的路径
effects menu click plus mirror
效果菜单点击+镜像
symmetry and now we have another copy
对称，现在我们有了另一个副本
over over there I'm going to grab the
在那边，我要去拿
edit paths by nodes tool I'm going to
按结点编辑路径工具我要转到
move this one over I'm going to hold
把这个搬过去，我要拿着
control while I'm doing this to make
控件，而我这样做是为了使
sure it stays locked on that same
当然，它会一直锁在那上面
horizontal axis that the other eye is on
另一只眼睛所在的水平轴
and now what I could do is I could take
现在我能做的就是
this object here hold shift take this
这个物体在这里按住Shift键拿着这个
object here with the nodes tool select
对象在此处使用节点工具选择
them both I'm going to turn on the
他们两个我都要打开
transformation handles like that and if
这样的变换句柄，如果
I select all of these nodes like that I
我像这样选择所有这些节点，即
can now take these nodes and scale these
现在可以利用这些节点并扩展这些
eyes up and down like that and as you
像这样上下看着，当你
can see whatever change I make to the
可以看到我对
one eye is also happening to the other
一只眼睛也发生在另一只眼睛上
eye and I can also rotate this around if
眼睛和我也可以旋转它，如果
i' like as you can see here I'm rotating
我就像你看到的，我在旋转
the eyes around I can move them over
周围的眼睛我可以把它们移开
like
喜欢
this maybe I'll deselect that I'll
这也许我会取消选择，我将
select just this one right here and I'll
只选这里的这一个，我就会
make this one whoops there we go make
做这件事我们要去做这件事
this one a little bigger like
这个稍微大一点，就像
that and I'm sure you get the idea
我相信你已经明白了
anything that I do to this grouping of
我对这群人所做的任何事情
objects will also happen to this
对象也将发生在此
grouping of objects over here
在这里分组的物体
okay so I'll take this one right here
好的，那么我就要这个了。
move this one
移走这一个
over maybe up a little bit turn off the
翻过来，也许再往上一点，关掉
transformation handles when I'm
变换句柄，当我
done and there you go that is how I was
做完了，你走了，这就是我
able to use the mirror symmetry tool to
能够使用镜像对称工具
create one eye and create a copy a
创建一只眼睛并创建一个副本
symmetry a mirror symmetry copy of the
对称：镜像对称副本
other eye and I can edit them together
另一只眼睛和我可以一起编辑
by just editing one of them so that is
只需编辑其中一个即可
just one example of how you can use the
这只是一个如何使用
mirror symmetry path effect in inkscape
墨迹中的镜像对称路径效应
if you found this lesson useful then
如果你觉得这一课很有用，那么
consider checking out my inkscape master
考虑一下我的Inkscape大师
class it's a collection of over 60
班级它是一个超过60个人的集合
videos where I go over all of the tools
我回顾所有工具的视频
and features in inkscape and I explain
墨水景观中的特征和我解释
what they are and demonstrate how they
它们是什么并展示它们如何
work kind of like how I did in this
工作有点像我在这件事上的表现
video we even have a private Community
视频我们甚至有一个私人社区
where you can ask questions and get help
您可以在那里提出问题并获得帮助
from me anytime you want and best of all
随时从我这里收到，最好的是
there's no monthly membership fees you
没有每月会员费
just pay $17 one time and you're in for
只需一次支付17美元，您就能获得
Life I'll have some information about
生活我会有一些信息
that down below if you want to check
如果你想检查的话，请在下面
that out as always thanks for watching
一如既往地感谢收看
oh
哦
[Music]
[音乐]